https://www.pickeringlabs.com/privacy-policy/#15

MenuProductsInstruments & ReagentsPost-column SystemsOnyx PCXPinnacle PCXVector PCXUVEReplacement ComponentsFlow Restrictors CloseAnalytical Columns & GuardsCation-exchange GARD™ Column Protection SystemLithium Amino Acid Analysis ColumnsSodium Amino Acid Analysis ColumnsCarbamate Pesticides Analysis ColumnsGlyphosate Herbicide Analysis ColumnsALKION™ ColumnsMycotox™ Mycotoxin Analysis ColumnsPolyether Antibiotics CloseReagents & ChemicalsReagents, Diluents & Sample PreparationTRIONE® Ninhydrin Reagento-phthalaldehydeNaphthalene-2,3-DicarboxaldehydeVANILLINp-Dimethylaminobenzaldehyde (DMAB)Thiofluor™ 2-(Dimethylamino)ethanethiol HClo-Phthalaldehyde-DiluentHydrolysis Reagent for Carbamate Pesticide Analysis CB130 & CB130.2Hypochlorite Diluent for Glyphosate Herbicide Analysis GA116Samples and Standards Diluents (Li220 & Na220)Solutions for Sample Preparation for Amino Acid Analysis (SERAPREP and URIPREP)ChlorAC™ BufferRestore™ CloseEluantsCalibration Standards & Test MixturesApplication KitsAmino Acid AnalysisEnvironmentalFood & Supplement Testing Close CloseClean-Up ProductsImmunoaffinity Sample Clean-up ColumnsDONeXGlyphosate & AMPA Sample Clean-up CloseApplicationsAmino Acid AnalysisMycotoxins AnalysisContaminants and ResidueFood / Feed / SupplementsHemp and Cannabis AnalysisProduct TestingArtificial PerspirationArtificial SalivaArtificial UrineOther Testing Products CloseSupportSupport ResourcesOnyx PCX SupportPinnacle PCX SupportVector PCX SupportMethod AbstractsSafety Data Sheets (SDS)Certificate of AnalysisContract LabsAmino Acid AnalysisEnvironmentalFoodDistributor List CloseLibraryMethod AbstractsAmino AcidsMycotoxinsContaminants and ResidueFood / Feed / SupplementsHemp and Cannabis AnalysisUser ManualsReagent BulletinsInstruction SheetsPrimersAmino Acid Analysis Part 1Amino Acid Analysis Part 2About Post-Column HPLCNewsroomCatalogs & BrochuresNewsletter Sign-upPress ReleasesWhite Papers CloseContact UsContact Information2020 CatalogDistributor ListAbout UsCompany OverviewInformation for DistributorsTerms & ConditionsContact PurchasingProduct Images & Specifications Close CloseBlog
Shop Online
Search
MenuProductsInstruments & ReagentsPost-column SystemsOnyx PCXPinnacle PCXVector PCXUVEReplacement ComponentsFlow Restrictors CloseAnalytical Columns & GuardsCation-exchange GARD™ Column Protection SystemLithium Amino Acid Analysis ColumnsSodium Amino Acid Analysis ColumnsCarbamate Pesticides Analysis ColumnsGlyphosate Herbicide Analysis ColumnsALKION™ ColumnsMycotox™ Mycotoxin Analysis ColumnsPolyether Antibiotics CloseReagents & ChemicalsReagents, Diluents & Sample PreparationTRIONE® Ninhydrin Reagento-phthalaldehydeNaphthalene-2,3-DicarboxaldehydeVANILLINp-Dimethylaminobenzaldehyde (DMAB)Thiofluor™ 2-(Dimethylamino)ethanethiol HClo-Phthalaldehyde-DiluentHydrolysis Reagent for Carbamate Pesticide Analysis CB130 & CB130.2Hypochlorite Diluent for Glyphosate Herbicide Analysis GA116Samples and Standards Diluents (Li220 & Na220)Solutions for Sample Preparation for Amino Acid Analysis (SERAPREP and URIPREP)ChlorAC™ BufferRestore™ CloseEluantsCalibration Standards & Test MixturesApplication KitsAmino Acid AnalysisEnvironmentalFood & Supplement Testing Close CloseClean-Up ProductsImmunoaffinity Sample Clean-up ColumnsDONeXGlyphosate & AMPA Sample Clean-up CloseApplicationsAmino Acid AnalysisMycotoxins AnalysisContaminants and ResidueFood / Feed / SupplementsHemp and Cannabis AnalysisProduct TestingArtificial PerspirationArtificial SalivaArtificial UrineOther Testing Products CloseSupportSupport ResourcesOnyx PCX SupportPinnacle PCX SupportVector PCX SupportMethod AbstractsSafety Data Sheets (SDS)Certificate of AnalysisContract LabsAmino Acid AnalysisEnvironmentalFoodDistributor List CloseLibraryMethod AbstractsAmino AcidsMycotoxinsContaminants and ResidueFood / Feed / SupplementsHemp and Cannabis AnalysisUser ManualsReagent BulletinsInstruction SheetsPrimersAmino Acid Analysis Part 1Amino Acid Analysis Part 2About Post-Column HPLCNewsroomCatalogs & BrochuresNewsletter Sign-upPress ReleasesWhite Papers CloseContact UsContact Information2020 CatalogDistributor ListAbout UsCompany OverviewInformation for DistributorsTerms & ConditionsContact PurchasingProduct Images & Specifications Close CloseBlog
Support
Privacy Notice
Who we are
Pickering Laboratories, Inc.
1280 Space Park Way
Mountain View, California 94043 USA
Our website addresses are: https://www.pickeringlabs.com and https://www.pickeringtestsolutions.com.
Table of Contents
1. Introduction
2. Effective date and changes to the Privacy Policy
3. Personal Data We Collect and Why We Collect It
4. How We Use Your Data
5. Who We Share Your Data With
6. Where Your Data is Stored and Used
7. How Long We Retain Your Data
8. What Rights You Have Over Your Data
9. California Privacy Rights
10. Children
11. How We Protect Personal Data
12. User ID and Password
13. Linking to Other Internet Sites
14. How You Can Access, Change and Delete Your Personal Data
15. Cookies and “Do Not Track” Signals
16. Data Breach Procedures and Notifications
17. Contact Information
1. Introduction
This Privacy Policy explains how Pickering Laboratories, Inc. (“Pickering Labs”) collects, uses, shares and protects Personal Data and Non-Personal Data on pickeringlabs.com and pickeringtestsolutions.com, social media sites and any other digital services and platforms operated or used by Pickering Labs as well as by phone or by paper.
2. Effective date and changes to the Privacy Policy
Pickering Labs will review and adjust our Privacy Policy at least on an annual basis; however, we reserve the right to revise the Privacy Policy at any time, for any reason. The effective date of this Privacy Policy revision is June 29, 2018.
3. Personal Data We Collect and Why We Collect It
Personal Data
Pickering Labs collects information online and by phone, fax and paper that enables us to identify or contact you so we may conduct and complete various business purposes, including but not limited to: creating a user account, requesting research articles and papers, joining our newsletter mail list, requesting information on our products and series, purchasing products or services, improving our websites, or otherwise interacting with the Pickering Labs.
The types of Personal Data we collect include, but are not limited to:
General data, such as names, addresses, email addresses, Internet protocol (IP) addresses, and telephone and cell phone numbers that are provided to us by our customers, vendors, and distributors.
Financial information needed to complete sales transactions, such as check account information, credit and debit card numbers, etc. Data are not stored or maintained online – financial information is only stored in our accounting software on our server.  After we transfer the information to Chase Bank for transaction processing, there is no online record of account information (https://www.chase.com/digital/resources/privacy-security).
Personal Data from third parties utilized for Pickering Labs’ marketing, information requests, and sales of our products and services.
Pickering Labs does not collect or store social security numbers, national identification numbers or tax identification numbers for customer or visitors to our websites. We only collect Government issued ID numbers for vendors, independent contractors, employees and others whom we pay for products and services.
Non-Personal Data
As you interact with our websites, Pickering Labs collects Non-Personal Data online that does not directly identify you.  The types of Non-Personal Data we collect include, but are not limited to:
Website usage such as browsing history, search terms, number of clicks, pages visited, date/time stamp, time on website
Computer type, operating system and platform type
Internet service provider
Internet protocol (IP) address
4. How We Use Your Data
In addition to the uses described above, we use your Personal Data and Non-Personal Data in a variety of ways such as:
Personal Data
Contact you.
Alert you about any potential changes or other news related to our company or products.
Provide payment reminders, order confirmations, and shipping information.
Fulfill and/or deliver Pickering Labs products and services.
Provide requested information on products and services or to provide information on products and services that you may find valuable.
Respond to your emails or online requests for products, services, or information.
Improve the performance and usability of our websites.
Publish a directory of international and domestic distributors.
Use your IP address to determine your country of origin. If you are an international visitor, we will use this information to redirect you to our list of suitable international distributors.
Non-Personal Data
Non-Personal Data is used to improve the performance and usability of our websites and our blog.
5.    Who We Share Your Data With
We share your Personal and Non-Personal Data in a variety of ways including, but not limited to the below:
Share data with third parties to fulfill service requests and to perform business functions such as data hosting services; web hosting services, email marketing and communication; packaging, mailing and delivering services; customer support and consulting services; and tradeshow registration services.
Share data with third parties if we believe it is reasonably necessary to do to detect and prevent fraud, security or technical issues, as well as to protect our personnel and property.
If legally required, share data with designated authorities.
Share data with third parties to offer you products and services that may be of interest to you professionally or personally.
You can request to opt-out of our mail lists at any time or have your data changed or purged from our systems. Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
Your email address will be used only by Pickering Labs, our entities, or vendors offering products and service on our behalf. We may also share email address with third parties that perform services on our behalf, such as packaging, mailing and delivering products and to respond to your service requests.
We do not sell or rent our email lists.
6. Where Your Data is Stored and Used:
Pickering Labs has an onsite data server and our IT consultants, TeamLogicIT, host an offsite back-up of our server.  Backup data is encrypted in transit and at rest and is retained for a period of up to 90 days. (https://www.teamlogicit.com/mountainviewca508/privacy-policy/).
We use Google Drive to store our newsletter email list and Google Analytics to analyze traffic data on our websites (https://privacy.google.com/businesses/compliance/#?modal_active=none).
Salesforce helps Pickering Labs build and manage sales leads, customer lists, technical support issue resolutions and marketing strategies (https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/).
Amazon lists and sells some of our products online (https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496).
Adagio Accounting Software from Softrak supports the accounting processes and audit controls of Pickering Labs. Adagio data is stored and maintained on our onsite server (https://softrak.com/privacy/online-privacy-policy).
We use AppRiver and Microsoft Outlook email programs. When you email Pickering Labs, it will be filtered and hosted by AppRiver.  Local copies of email may exist on individual workstations in the form of cached data in Microsoft Outlook (https://www.appriver.com/privacy-policy/; https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement).
Shipping Services: Pickering Labs uses UPS and UPS Quantum View software, FedEX and FedEX Express software, and DHL’s webpage to provide shipping services to our customers (https://www.ups.com/us/en/help-center/legal-terms-conditions/privacy-notice.page?; http://www.fedex.com/images/us/2011crimages/CPC/FedEx_Privacy_Notice.pdf;  http://www.dhl.com/en/legal.html#privacy).
Vertical Response is Pickering Labs’ email marketing and bulk communications platform (https://www.deluxe.com/policy/privacy-shield). We have implemented a double opt-in form process to make sure you receive the communications from us that you wish to receive. Email lists are stored online with Vertical Response.  You always have the ability to opt-out or change your contact information. Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
Chase Bank is Pickering Labs’ sole payment processor. Pickering Labs does not keep online records of credit or debit card numbers or checking account information – we transfer this information to Chase Bank where they process and manage all financial information and transactions (https://www.chase.com/digital/resources/privacy-security). We do not collect or maintain credit card or checking account information online.
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
IP addresses are collected and used to determine your country of origin. If you are an international visitor looking to purchase products online, our websites will automatically redirect you to a list of our international distributors.
Our security software logs email and IP addresses of detected spammers. This information is used to block them from spamming our blog and forms.
7. How Long We Retain Your Data
The following describes some of the data types we collect and the length of time we retain that information:
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register or create an account on our websites, we will store your personal information in a user profile online and/or offline. You can review, edit, or delete your personal information at any time (except you cannot change your username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
All financial transaction information (credit card, checking, etc.) is processed and managed by Chase Bank (https://www.chase.com/digital/resources/privacy-security). Pickering Labs does not store or manage credit card or checking information online. After the sales transaction is transferred to Chase Bank for processing, there is no online record of account information.
We keep paper copies of sales transactions for at least 5 years and up to 6 years before they are physically destroyed.  These transactions may contain email addresses and phone numbers along with shipping and billing addresses.
We keep electronic accounting records indefinitely for active accounts in our Adagio accounting software on our onsite server.  Customer accounts can be inactivated and individual/personal data can be removed such as email addresses and phone numbers, which effectively keep the company’s transaction history but removes personal data.  Invoices paid by credit or debit card may have electronic record of the account number stored in the individual transaction data.  Credit card numbers are not maintained in customer accounts unless explicitly requested by customer.
Our security software logs email and IP addresses of detected spammers. We keep this information indefinitely to block them from spamming our blog and forms.
Pickering Labs’ onsite data server is backed up offsite by our IT consultants, TeamLogicIT, and backup data is retained for a period of up to 90 days.
You can review, edit, or delete your personal information at any time. Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
8. What Rights You Have Over Your Data
If you register on pickeringlabs.com in order to leave blog post comments or to shop for our products and services online, we will store your personal information in a user profile where you can see, edit, or delete your personal information at any time (except that you may not be able to change your username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
Pickeringtestsolutions.com does not require a user profile for purchases and has no blog, so no online user registrations are needed. Online sales data is inputted, printed by the customer, and sent to Pickering Labs’ customer service via email.
If you have requested information, left comments, asked to be added to our mail list, or if you have created an account or user profile, you can request for Pickering Labs to provide a readout of your personal data, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we delete your personal data from our systems. This does not include any data we are obligated to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
You can manage your profile and email preferences, including “opting out” of email. Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
9. California Privacy Right
In addition to the rights as explained in this Privacy Policy, under the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), California residents who provide personal information (as defined in the statute) to obtain products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us, twice a calendar year, information about the personal information we shared, if any, with other businesses for marketing purposes. If applicable, this information would include the categories of personal information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared such personal information during the prior 12 months.
CCPA also gives you the right to request what personal information is collected on you and how we use it. You can make this request without fear of retaliation.
As stated in other parts of this Privacy Policy, Pickering Laboratories does not sell personal information.  If  for any reason you would like to opt-out of our newsletter, modify your current information or have it removed from our servers, you made do so at any time by contacting support@pickeringlabs.com.
The CCPA allows for a number of exemptions on how we can use your data, such as:
We must comply with federal, state, or local laws
We must cooperate with requests from legal and enforcement agencies
We can use your information to defend legal claims
We can collect, use, retain, or disclose consumer information that can’t be identified or is aggregated consumer information
Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
10. Children
We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from or market to children under the age of 16.  If we learn that we have collected the Personal Data of a child under 16, or equivalent minimum age depending on jurisdiction, we will delete the information as soon as possible.
Children under 18 are not allowed to open an account or purchase items on pickeringlabs.com or pickeringtestsolutions.com.
11. How We Protect Personal Data
Pickering Labs uses reasonable security measures to help protect your personal data against unauthorized access. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is fully secure; therefore, we cannot guarantee or warranty the security of the Personal Data you transmit to us, or to or from our online websites.
Pickering Labs secures your information during transmission with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.  In addition, data is protected by log-in procedures. Back-ups and replications of data are encrypted and password protected. Our network is protected by a hardware based, stateful inspection firewall.  Data protection is in place via endpoint protection software provided by a global, reputable security company.  Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
Please note that it is extremely important for you to protect yourself against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer.
12. User ID and Password
Certain areas of our websites require a user ID, email address, or password as an additional security measure that helps to protect your Personal Data.  To help you protect your privacy, our websites have tools to help you log in and log out, and to change and edit your personal information.
13. Linking to Other Internet Sites
Please be aware that we may provide links from our websites and email communications to third party websites such as our list of international distributors and partner vendors. These third party websites have their own set of privacy policies that may differ from ours. To ensure your privacy is protected, we recommend that you review the privacy statements of these linked sites, applications, or other digital platforms.
14. How You Can Access, Change and Delete Your Personal Data
Please keep your personal data updated and correct.  If you have an account or subscription to one of our websites or mail lists, you can review, update or delete your information directly on our website or by contacting us. Please see our “Contact Us” section below for more information.
15. Cookies and “Do Not Track” Signals
Cookies Overview
Cookies are small text files placed on your device to store data that can be recalled by a web server in the domain that placed the cookie. We use cookies for our online shopping accounts, Google Analytics, and to improve the performance of our websites. You agree to our use of cookies by continuing to use our website(s).
Cookie settings can be controlled through your Internet browser.  If you block our cookies, though, some features and functionality of our websites will not operate as expected.
Cookies Associated With Our Blog:
If you leave a comment on our website, you can use cookies to save your name, email address, website, etc. These cookies are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture will become visible to the public in the context of your comment.
When you log in to our websites, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Cookies Associated With Our Website Software and Plugins
Several of our plugins use cookies. For example, our popup builder will set a cookie so it will limit the number of popups it makes available to you. Our cookie notice (required by the European Union) sets a cookie when you agree to our use of cookies. When its cookie is set and valid, you will not see the popup again until the cookie is removed.
Cookies Associated With Our Online Shopping
Our online shopping carts use cookies to remember your login, preferences, cart selections, etc.  The cookies are designed to greatly improve your online shopping experience.
Cookies Associated With Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics. Google Analytics places a persistent cookie in a user’s browser so the software can track website usage such as browsing history, search terms, number of clicks, pages visited, date/time stamp, time on website. This information is used for general reporting purposes. Please see Google’s privacy policy for additional information about their data protection, collection and use.  Also, please review their documentation regarding their use of IP addresses and cookies (https://policies.google.com/privacy/).
“Do Not Track” Signals
We are committed to protecting your personal data, and we will only share your information in situations described in the privacy policy.  Since all users are protected equally under this policy, we do not change our actions in response to a web browser’s “do not track” signal.
If you do not want Google Analytics to collect and track your data, you may opt-out on your own by downloading Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.  For more information go to https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
16. Data Breach Procedures and Notifications
If Pickering Labs or our IT vendor detects a data security breach, we will:
Notify the proper authorities
Notify our IT management firm (TeamLogicIT)
Determine next steps as per FTC/FBI guidelines based upon the type of data breached. Please note that:
We do not collect personal information such as government IDs, date of birth, etc.
We do not store or maintain online records of financial information (credit card numbers, checking accounts, etc.) and we do not collect this information online.
Invoices paid by credit or debit card may have an electronic record of the account number stored in the individual transaction data within our Adagio accounting software on our onsite server.
Where applicable, we will take steps to notify client(s) of data breached.
17. Contact Information
If you have questions, comments, or if you wish to change, access, or remove your Personal Data, please contact us at:
Pickering Laboratories, Inc.
1280 Space Park Way
Mountain View, California 94043 USA
https://www.pickeringlabs.com/contact-us/
1 (800) 654-3330 or +1 (650) 694-6700 or support@pickeringlabs.com
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.
–
–
–
Products
Instruments & Reagents
Application Notes
Product Testing
Support
Customer Notification of Pickering In-Service
We will be closed on Friday, December 11th. Normal operations will resume on Monday, December 14th.
Thank you for your patience during our upcoming closure.
Customer Service: orders@pickeringlabs.com
Technical Support: support@pickeringlabs.com
Phone: 650-694-6700
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use our site, you accept our use of cookies and revised Privacy Policy.Accept
